const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which neurotransmitter acts on the presynaptic membrane as an inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma-aminobutyric acid (GABA)","bool":true},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which neurotransmitter is secreted by the Raphe nuclei that also plays a role in non-REM sleep?","answers":[{"option":"Gamma-aminobutyric acid (GABA)","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Noradrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true},{"option":"Adrenaline","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which dural reflection separates the cerebrum from the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Tentorium cerebelli","bool":true},{"option":"Falx cerebelli","bool":false},{"option":"Falx cerebri","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragma sellae","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the main chemical constituent of the insulating sheaths on myelinated neurons?","answers":[{"option":"Galactocerebroside","bool":false},{"option":"Cholestrol","bool":false},{"option":"Choline","bool":false},{"option":"Sphingomyelin","bool":true},{"option":"Phosphagen","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following cavities is present in the midbrain?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":true},{"option":"Fourth ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Monro","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"Third ventricle","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A 56-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with facial and limb paralysis. An examination also reveals that he has pupils reduced to the size of pinpoints. A hemorrhage is suspected. A computed tomography (CT) scan is performed. The CT image will show a hemorrhage at which of the following regions?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":true},{"option":"Mid-brain","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which statement is false regarding axon structure and function?","answers":[{"option":"Transmit action potential","bool":false},{"option":"Axons can arise from dendrites","bool":false},{"option":"Axons can arise from soma","bool":false},{"option":"Nissl substance is present","bool":true},{"option":"Axons can arise from hillock","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is a motor neuron, along with the skeletal muscle fibers innervated by that particular neuron, collectively called?","answers":[{"option":"Motor unit","bool":true},{"option":"Primary motor area","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle spindle","bool":false},{"option":"Motor complex","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi tendon organ (GTO)","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A 30-year-old man reported to the emergency department with a complaint of a dog bite on the right arm. The casualty is conscious but the wound is bleeding. No previous medical or surgical history is reported. After history taking, what is the first step of management?","answers":[{"option":"Testing the dog for rabies","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of anti-rabies immunoglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of IV saline","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of anti-rabies vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Washing and debridement of the wound","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which neurotransmitter is most commonly released by pre-ganglionic sympathetic neurons?","answers":[{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma-aminobutyric acid (GABA)","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":true},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following amino acids is serotonin derived from?","answers":[{"option":"Arginine","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":true},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following cavities is present in the diencephalon?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Third ventricle","bool":true}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"The neostriatum consists of which of the following pairs of structures?","answers":[{"option":"Putamen and caudate nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Putamen and globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Lentiform and globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Lentiform and caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen and lentiform nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"The suprachiasmatic nucleus is responsible for which of the following functions?","answers":[{"option":"Regulation of body's circadian rhythym","bool":true},{"option":"Release of anti-diuretic hormone (ADH)","bool":false},{"option":"Thermoregulation","bool":false},{"option":"Control of feeding impulses","bool":false},{"option":"Release of oxytocin","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a superficial reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Plantar reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Conjunctival reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Abdominal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Patellar reflex","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is associated with an enlargement of the posterior cranial fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Holoprosencephaly","bool":false},{"option":"Arnold-Chiari type I","bool":false},{"option":"Arnold-Chiari type II","bool":false},{"option":"Agenesis of the corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Dandy-walker syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a deep tendon reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Patellar reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Biceps reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Ankle reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Brachioradialis reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Conjunctival reflex","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the sensitivity to the stimuli outside the body called?","answers":[{"option":"Kinesthesia","bool":false},{"option":"Interoception","bool":false},{"option":"Exteroception","bool":true},{"option":"Nociception","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioception","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the rate of production of cerebrospinal fluid (CSF)?","answers":[{"option":"250-300 ml/day","bool":false},{"option":"500-550 ml/day","bool":true},{"option":"350-400 ml/day","bool":false},{"option":"150-200 ml/day","bool":false},{"option":"50-150 ml/day","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A 26-year-old man comes to the outpatient department (OPD) with a high fever and cold sores around the mouth. Lab investigations reveal lymphocytosis, red blood cells (RBCs), and normal glucose in the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF). What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Herpes encephalitis","bool":true},{"option":"Fungal encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"West Nile fever","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Protozoal encephalitis","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is another name for the hemisection of the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Weber syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Brown-Sequard syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Syringomyelia","bool":false},{"option":"Wallenburg sydnrome","bool":false},{"option":"Benedikt syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Holoprosencephaly is a malformation characterized by an inability of the cerebral hemispheres to separate at the midline. Which genetic disorder is this malformation associated with?","answers":[{"option":"Trisomy 13","bool":true},{"option":"Trisomy 21","bool":false},{"option":"Trisomy 17","bool":false},{"option":"Trisomy 15","bool":false},{"option":"Trisomy 18","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which cranial nerve nucleus is present at the level of the superior colliculus?","answers":[{"option":"Trochlear nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal nucleus of vagus","bool":false},{"option":"Facial motor nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nucleus","bool":true}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is the corpus striatum a part of?","answers":[{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":true},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Limbic system","bool":false},{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the cerebellum embryologically derived from?","answers":[{"option":"Rhombencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Telencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Myelencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Metencephalon","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which one of the following nerves passes through foramen rotundum?","answers":[{"option":"Lesser petrosal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which one of the following is not a dural fold?","answers":[{"option":"Diaphragma sellae","bool":false},{"option":"Falx cerebri","bool":false},{"option":"Tentorium cerebelli","bool":false},{"option":"Falx cerebelli","bool":false},{"option":"Hypophysis cerebri","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A lesion in which structure will cause athetosis?","answers":[{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":false},{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":true},{"option":"Caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which one of the following is a function of the sympathetic nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Vasoconstriction","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased heart rate","bool":false},{"option":"Increased GIT motility","bool":false},{"option":"Defecation","bool":false},{"option":"Pupil constriction","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which hypothalamic nuclei are responsible for decreasing heart rate and blood pressure, and increasing the contraction of the urinary bladder?","answers":[{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior and preoptic nuclei","bool":true},{"option":"Supraoptic and paraventricular nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral hypothalamic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior and lateral nuclei","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which one of the following structures is the largest component of the diencephalon?","answers":[{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which one of the following is not true about the cerebellar cortex?","answers":[{"option":"It has six distinct layers","bool":true},{"option":"It has a middle Purkinje layer","bool":false},{"option":"It has three distinct layers","bool":false},{"option":"It has an inner granular layer","bool":false},{"option":"It has an outer molecular layer","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following amino acids is required for the synthesis of dopamine, epinephrine and norepinephrine?","answers":[{"option":"Valine","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":true},{"option":"Methionine","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A newborn baby was brought to the neurology outpatient department because the large size of the fetal head-MRI shows fluid in the lateral ventricle. The appropriate part of the lateral ventricle formed by the head of the caudate nucleus is?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior horn","bool":true},{"option":"Medial horn","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior horn","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior horn","bool":false},{"option":"Superior horn","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the frequency range of alpha waves?","answers":[{"option":"14-80 cycles per second","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 3.5 cycles per second","bool":false},{"option":"4-7 cycles per second","bool":false},{"option":"8-13 cycles per second","bool":true},{"option":"35-140 cycles per second","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A 36-year-old man fell from a height of 10 feet. As a consequence, he now suffers from incontinence and weakness in the lower limbs. Which of the following statements is correct?","answers":[{"option":"The middle cerebral artery is involved","bool":false},{"option":"The posterior cerebral artery is involved","bool":false},{"option":"Imaging of lumbosacral region should be done","bool":true},{"option":"Involvement of cervical spine C4 level","bool":false},{"option":"Imaging of dorsal spine should be done","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the rate of nerve regeneration after an injury?","answers":[{"option":"100 mm/day","bool":false},{"option":"200 mm/day","bool":false},{"option":"8 mm/day","bool":false},{"option":"0.1 mm/day","bool":false},{"option":"3 mm/day","bool":true}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which statement is incorrect about pyramidal cell morphology?","answers":[{"option":"The axon arises from the base of the cell body","bool":false},{"option":"Betz cells are present in the superficial layer","bool":true},{"option":"Dendrites from the apex are highly branched and extend to the surface","bool":false},{"option":"Short lateral dendrites extend from the base","bool":false},{"option":"The apices point towards the pial surface of the cortex","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which types of cells are not present in the cerebellar cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Stellate cells","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidal cells","bool":true},{"option":"Golgi cells","bool":false},{"option":"Granule cells","bool":false},{"option":"Basket cells","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following structures is NOT present on the medial side of the cerebrum?","answers":[{"option":"Insula","bool":true},{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Paracentral lobule","bool":false},{"option":"Cuneus","bool":false},{"option":"Precuneus","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"The caudate nucleus, putamen, and the globus pallidus collectively make up which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Limbic system","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false},{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":false},{"option":"Basal nuclei","bool":true}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Ischemia of the dorsal and lateral parts of the medulla will not present with which of the following symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Paralysis of tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Gait and limb ataxia","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of pain","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of temperature sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Dysarthria","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What signs and symptoms will be observed as a consequence of a lesion in Wernicke's area?","answers":[{"option":"Inability to produce fluent speech","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to understand written or spoken words","bool":true},{"option":"Inability to appreciate texture of objects","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to read or write","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to interpret sounds","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is an indolamine derived from tryptophan?","answers":[{"option":"Leukotriene","bool":false},{"option":"Prostaglandin","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true},{"option":"Chitin","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is formed by efferent fibers from the red nucleus to the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Olivospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibulospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Rubrospinal tract","bool":true},{"option":"Reticulospinal tract","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is inappropriate regarding Kluver-Bucy syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Lack of emotions","bool":false},{"option":"Placidity","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral motor paralysis","bool":true},{"option":"Increased sexual drive","bool":false},{"option":"Increased hunger","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is Parkinson's disease characterized by?","answers":[{"option":"Agitation","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperkinesia","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellar tremor","bool":false},{"option":"Both bradykinesia and hyperkinesia","bool":true},{"option":"Hypokinesia","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the function of the reticular activating system?","answers":[{"option":"Control of emotion and behavior","bool":false},{"option":"Control of the autonomic functions","bool":false},{"option":"Alertness and wakefulness","bool":true},{"option":"Sensory relay","bool":false},{"option":"Memory","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following visual reflexes involves the cerebral cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Corneal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Direct pupillary reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Consensual reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation reflex","bool":true},{"option":"Visual body reflex","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which anatomical feature is present on the anterior surface of the pons?","answers":[{"option":"Sulcus limitans","bool":false},{"option":"Basilar groove","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibular area","bool":false},{"option":"Facial colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Median sulcus","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Lesion of the dorsal column results in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of pain sensations","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory ataxia","bool":true},{"option":"Apraxia","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of temperature sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Motor ataxia","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is another name for the hindbrain?","answers":[{"option":"Rhombencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Metencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Myelencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalon","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A 78-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with a tremor that disappears on movement. The doctor suspects the possibility of a lesion in his brain. Where is the lesion most likely to be located?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which nucleus of the hypothalamus contains the satiety center?","answers":[{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Posterolateral nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Paraventricular nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common and dangerous site of thrombosis?","answers":[{"option":"Superior saggital sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Cavernous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior petrosal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Straight sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior saggital sinus","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is a reflex that develops over time?","answers":[{"option":"Abdominal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Watering of mouth","bool":true},{"option":"Plantar reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Where is the choroid plexus located?","answers":[{"option":"Floor of lateral ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Floor of fourth ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Floor of third ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Roof of third ventricle","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral boundary of fourth ventricle","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"The medial geniculate body (MGB) receives input from which of the following sensory pathways?","answers":[{"option":"Olfactory","bool":false},{"option":"Auditory","bool":true},{"option":"Tactile","bool":false},{"option":"Optic","bool":false},{"option":"Gustatory","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is an autoimmune disease affecting the nicotinic acetylcholine receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Guillain-Barré syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Myasthenia gravis","bool":true},{"option":"Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD)","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Lesions of the supraoptic and paraventricular nuclei would result in which of the following disorders?","answers":[{"option":"Kallman syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Korsakoff syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes insipidus","bool":true},{"option":"Kluver-Bucy syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Disturbances in circadian rhythms","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"The dorsal column pathway is best tested by checking which of the following sensations?","answers":[{"option":"Vibration","bool":true},{"option":"Temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Unconscious proprioception","bool":false},{"option":"Light touch","bool":false},{"option":"Pain","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following hypothalamic nucleus is responsible for increasing the heart rate and blood pressure?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberomamillary nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Agenesis of the corpus callosum is associated with which of the following symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Mental retardation","bool":true},{"option":"Loss of sensory control","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of coordination","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of speech","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of motor contrtol","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A 25-year-old-man comes to the outpatient department with complaints of an altered sense of smell after sustaining an injury to the area of the brain where the hypothalamus is located. In which associated structure is the lesion most likely to be located?","answers":[{"option":"Mamillothalamic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Medial forebrain bundle","bool":true},{"option":"Thalamohypothalamic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdalohypothalamic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Tegmental fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Subdural space is located between which of the following layers?","answers":[{"option":"Dura mater and pia mater","bool":false},{"option":"Arachnoid mater and dura mater","bool":true},{"option":"Pia mater and arachnoid mater","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Suckling causes the release of oxytocin from which of the hypothalamus nuclei?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":false},{"option":"Supraoptic","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic","bool":false},{"option":"Paraventricular","bool":true}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"The ventral lateral nucleus of the thalamus is concerned with which of the following functions?","answers":[{"option":"Circadian rhythm","bool":false},{"option":"Alertness","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory control","bool":false},{"option":"Consciousness","bool":false},{"option":"Motor activity","bool":true}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following structures is responsible for the production of cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Choroid plexus","bool":true},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"How is the level of consciousness of a patient tested?","answers":[{"option":"Glasgow coma scale","bool":true},{"option":"Higher mental function","bool":false},{"option":"Gait disturbances","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Deep tendon reflexes","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"The brain magnetic resonance image (MRI) of an 8-year-old child shows a bat-wing deformity. Which condition is the most likely cause of this?","answers":[{"option":"Lissencephaly","bool":false},{"option":"Holoprosencephaly","bool":false},{"option":"Polymicrogyria","bool":false},{"option":"Neuronal heterotopia","bool":false},{"option":"Agenesis of corpus callosum","bool":true}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Hyperorality, hypersexuality, and decreased emotions are all associated with which syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Dandy-Walker syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Klüver-Bucy syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Guillain-Barré syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Wernicke-Korsakoff syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamic pain syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"The blood-brain barrier is formed by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Tight junctions between capillary endothelial cells","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Pericytes present around the capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"The impermeable, non-fenestrated, basement membrane of the capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudopods of the astrocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Pain and temperature sensations are carried by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Rubrospinal pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Spinocerebellar pathway","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the function of the Golgi tendon organ?","answers":[{"option":"Damage the contractile forces","bool":false},{"option":"Prevent extreme contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Equalize forces between individual muscle fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibit the force","bool":false},{"option":"Nullify the contractile forces","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is a neuron that forms synaptic junctions with intrafusal skeletal muscle fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Purkinje cell","bool":false},{"option":"Granule cell","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma motor neuron","bool":true},{"option":"Alpha motor neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidal cell","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which statement is incorrect about Wallerian degeneration?","answers":[{"option":"It occurs in the peripheral nervous system (PNS)","bool":false},{"option":"It is retrograde","bool":true},{"option":"The axon and the myelin sheath disappear","bool":false},{"option":"It occurs in the central nervous system (CNS)","bool":false},{"option":"Schwann cells proliferate","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which structure(s) acts as the second-order neuron of the dorsal column?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleus cuneatus and gracilis","bool":true},{"option":"Clarke's column","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus dorsalis","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Increased protein in cerebrospinal fluid occurs in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Increased intracranial pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial infection","bool":true},{"option":"Repeated lumbar puncture","bool":false},{"option":"Acute water intoxication","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which structure acts as the second-order neuron for the spinothalamic tract?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleus gracilis","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia gelatinosa","bool":true},{"option":"Nucleus cuneatus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus dorsalis","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following clinical features will be seen in a lesion of the cerebellar hemisphere?","answers":[{"option":"Negative Romberg sign","bool":true},{"option":"Tremors in the right hand","bool":false},{"option":"Swaying left to right with eyes closed","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased muscle tone in the right upper and lower limbs","bool":false},{"option":"Person falls to the right","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the function of acetylcholinesterase?","answers":[{"option":"To esterify acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"To synthesize acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"To add acetyl group to choline","bool":false},{"option":"To add ester group to choline","bool":false},{"option":"To hydrolyze acetylcholine","bool":true}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"The internal cerebral vein is formed by the union of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial and deep middle cerebral vein","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebral vein and striate vein","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamostriate and choroidal veins","bool":true},{"option":"Superior cerebral vein and the great cerebral vein","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial cerebral vein and the basal vein","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Glucose enters the brain through which of the following transporters?","answers":[{"option":"GLUT-4","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT-2","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT-13","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT-1","bool":true},{"option":"SGLT-1","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding a watershed infarct?","answers":[{"option":"It is seen after hypotensive episodes","bool":false},{"option":"It may occur at the borderzone between anterior and middle cerebral arteries","bool":true},{"option":"It occurs when there is liquefactive necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"A paradoxical occurrence in which ischemic area becomes infused with cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) and life-threatening cerebral edema ensues","bool":false},{"option":"It occurs due to hyperviscosity of blood","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following symptoms will be the result of a lesion of the intermediate zone of the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Vertigo","bool":false},{"option":"Nystagmus","bool":false},{"option":"Dysarthia","bool":false},{"option":"Resting tremor","bool":false},{"option":"Dysdiadochokinesia","bool":true}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the pathophysiology behind schizophrenia?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Increased glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"Increased dopamine","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A 25-year-old man develops thrombosis of the anterior spinal artery. Which of the following regions will be affected the most?","answers":[{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":true},{"option":"Mid-brain","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following hypothalamic nuclei regulates circadian rhythms?","answers":[{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"The cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) leaves the lateral ventricles to flow into the third ventricle through which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Cisterna Magna","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Magendie","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Luschka","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Monro","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect about alpha fibers?","answers":[{"option":"They are inhibited by Renshaw cells","bool":false},{"option":"They attach to intrafusal fibers","bool":true},{"option":"They are greater than gamma fibers","bool":false},{"option":"They are efferent fibers of the lower motors neuron","bool":false},{"option":"They attach to extrafusal fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"In a T2WI section magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), the intervertebral disc appears as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Grey","bool":false},{"option":"Black","bool":false},{"option":"Jet black","bool":false},{"option":"Dark","bool":false},{"option":"Bright","bool":true}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following terms correctly describes the degeneration of the distal cut end of the neuron?","answers":[{"option":"Synaptic stripping","bool":false},{"option":"Chromatolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Retrograde degeneration","bool":false},{"option":"Wallerian degeneration","bool":true}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"An autopsy of the brain of a 40-year-old man reveals transtentorial herniation. Further examination reveals flame-shaped lesions in the midbrain and pons. Which term best describes this?","answers":[{"option":"Saccular aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Duret hemorrhages","bool":true},{"option":"Intraparenchymal hemorrhages","bool":false},{"option":"Slit hemorrhages","bool":false},{"option":"Lacunar infarcts","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following brain structures is responsible for emotional memory?","answers":[{"option":"Amygdala","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect about the central nervous system gray matter?","answers":[{"option":"It is only present in the cerebral region","bool":true},{"option":"It is present in all segments","bool":false},{"option":"Gray matter is unmyelinated","bool":false},{"option":"It surrounds the central canal","bool":false},{"option":"It is H-shaped","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following characterizes upper motor neuron lesions?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoactive muscle stretch reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Flaccid paralysis","bool":false},{"option":"Fasiculations","bool":false},{"option":"Disuse atrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased muscle tone","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Agenesis of the corpus callosum is characterized by which of the following observations?","answers":[{"option":"Commissural fibres are not connected","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased gray matter bundles","bool":false},{"option":"Increased white matter bundles","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral hemispheres are not connected","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased white matter bundles","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct about the cerebellar cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Mossy fibers travel through the inferior cerebellar peduncle","bool":true},{"option":"Golgi type I cells are found in the granular layer","bool":false},{"option":"Climbing fibers terminate in glomeruli of granular layer and synapse with both granule cells and Golgi type II cells","bool":false},{"option":"Climbing fibers originate from the superior olivary nucleus of the pons","bool":false},{"option":"Dendrites of Golgi type II extend throughout the cerebellar cortex","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following structures are constituents of the limbic system?","answers":[{"option":"Cingulate gyrus and the uncus","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdaloid nucleus, red nucleus, and vestibular nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampal formation","bool":false},{"option":"Pulvinar of the thalamus and substantia nigra","bool":false},{"option":"Subcallosal, cingulate and parahippocampal gyri, hippocampal formation, amygdaloid nucleus, mammillary body and anterior thalamic nuclei","bool":true}]},{"id":99,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following statements regarding the blood-brain barrier is true?","answers":[{"option":"It is well-developed in infants and children and becomes less efficient with age","bool":false},{"option":"It allows restricted passage of water and gases","bool":false},{"option":"The structure of the blood-brain barrier is identical in all areas of the nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"It is absent in aggressive tumors of the brain","bool":true},{"option":"Drugs that are highly protein-bound can easily cross the blood-brain barrier","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Encephalocele most commonly involves which cranial fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Medial cranial fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cranial fossa","bool":true},{"option":"Middle cranial fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cranial fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral cranial fossa","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which receptors receive stimuli immediate from external surroundings?","answers":[{"option":"Enteroreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Teloreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Chemoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Exteroreceptors","bool":true}]},{"id":102,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which one of the following forms the blood-brain barrier?","answers":[{"option":"Osteocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle cells","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Neurons","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"The nerve endings at the end of the receptor have a receptor potential due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Excitatory post synaptic potential","bool":false},{"option":"End plate potential","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation","bool":false},{"option":"Adaptation","bool":false},{"option":"Change in potential","bool":true}]},{"id":104,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Neurons after injury become red because of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Eosinophilia","bool":true},{"option":"Infiltration","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Amyloid deposition","bool":false},{"option":"Shrinkage of nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Sensory feedback helps the motor cortex to control which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Precise muscle movements","bool":true},{"option":"Eye movement","bool":false},{"option":"Hormones secretion from the hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Oscillation of vestibular system","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A lesion in which of the following is responsible for the symptoms of a man with resting tremors which disappear when working?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"The limbic cortex is a part of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Rhombencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Prosencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Telencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Mesencephalon","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following tracts is spared in anterior cord syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Corticobulbar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Parkinson's disease involves degeneration of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":true},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus striatum","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Where is the respiratory center located?","answers":[{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is responsible for normal maintenance of tone and equilibrium?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":true},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following structures is related to the auditory system in pons?","answers":[{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezoid body","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Spiral ganglion","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is correct regarding the Schwann cells?","answers":[{"option":"One Schwann cell covers 30 nerve fibers","bool":false},{"option":"They are produced in the central nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis is a demyelinating disorder that affects the Schwann cells","bool":false},{"option":"Schwann cells cover all cranial nerves","bool":false},{"option":"They are produced in the peripheral nervous system","bool":true}]},{"id":114,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is a sign of lower motor neuron (LMN) lesions?","answers":[{"option":"Spasticity","bool":false},{"option":"Clasp-knife response","bool":false},{"option":"Flaccid paralysis","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperactive stretch reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Disuse atrophy","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Inhibitory postsynaptic potential is caused by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Chloride influx","bool":true},{"option":"Bicarbonate influx","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium influx","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium influx","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium influx","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"According to the World Health Organization, how long is the loss of cerebral function for it to be called a stroke?","answers":[{"option":"More than 3 minutes","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 1 hour","bool":false},{"option":"More than 1 hour","bool":false},{"option":"Atleast 3 days","bool":false},{"option":"More than 24 hours","bool":true}]},{"id":117,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding dural venous sinuses?","answers":[{"option":"They are present between the arachnoid and dura mater","bool":true},{"option":"The flow is bidirectional","bool":false},{"option":"They are devoid of smooth muscles","bool":false},{"option":"They are lined by endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"They have no valves","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"The cerebrospinal fluid leaves the fourth ventricle through which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Arachnoid villi","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Monro","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":false},{"option":"Central canal","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Magendie","bool":true}]},{"id":119,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Lacunar infarcts are caused by hypertension in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Large sized artery","bool":false},{"option":"Medium sized artery","bool":false},{"option":"Communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Penetrating artery","bool":true}]},{"id":120,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"An old man was having difficulty in walking and maintaining his posture. A lesion in which of the following structures will cause these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior lobe of cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior lobe of cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Flocculonodular lobe","bool":true},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"An obese woman suffers from a mid-hypothalamic lesion. Which of the following nuclei is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior hypothalamic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventromedial hypothalamic nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Preoptic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which one of the following is formed by cells in the alar plate?","answers":[{"option":"Autonomic ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Motor neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior gray horn","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior gray horn","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is meant by paresthesia?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of pain sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Pins and needles sensation","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Increased sensitivity","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"In a T2WI section magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), the cerebrospinal fluid appears as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Jet black","bool":false},{"option":"Dark","bool":false},{"option":"Black","bool":false},{"option":"Bright","bool":true},{"option":"Grey","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the function of muscle spindles?","answers":[{"option":"Detect dynamic and static changes in muscle length","bool":true},{"option":"Detect muscle tension","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Detect muscle strength","bool":false},{"option":"Detect muscle shape","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is responsible for dynamic and static control of muscle spindles?","answers":[{"option":"Gamma motor neurons","bool":true},{"option":"Beta motor neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Intrafusal nuclear chain","bool":false},{"option":"Withdrawal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha motor neurons","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"In adults, 40-60% energy is provided by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Lipids","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamins","bool":false},{"option":"Minerals","bool":false},{"option":"Carbohydrates","bool":true},{"option":"Nucleic acids","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A 6-month-old child suffering from encephalocele has a 6 x 6 cm protrusion on his head. Which of the following would be present in the protrusion?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Meninges","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Blood","bool":false},{"option":"Brain and meninges","bool":true}]},{"id":129,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following happens in Parkinson's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Dopaminergic neurons are destroyed","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"D3 receptors are destroyed","bool":false},{"option":"D1 receptors are destroyed","bool":false},{"option":"D2 receptors are destroyed","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Where are beta waves commonly observed?","answers":[{"option":"Temporal lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal and occipital lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal and frontal lobe","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal lobe","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following sends signals to the primary motor area?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Premotor area","bool":true},{"option":"Olfactory bulb","bool":false},{"option":"Visual cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Cingulate cortex","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is the main input unit of basal ganglia?","answers":[{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Caudate and putamen","bool":true},{"option":"Subthalamic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which one of the following structures is not part of the sub limbic cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false},{"option":"Septal nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false}]}]
export default arr